<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<EmailTemplate xmlns="http://soap.sforce.com/2006/04/metadata">
    <available>true</available>
    <encodingKey>ISO-8859-1</encodingKey>
    <letterhead>Monash_MGE_Standard</letterhead>
    <name>Revise thesis summary</name>
    <style>freeForm</style>
    <subject>Thesis summary: «STDNT_FULL_NAME»</subject>
    <textOnly>Dear {!Case.Contact},


Congratulations on your recent submission We are almost ready to dispatch the thesis for examination.


Regretfully, your thesis summary needs to be shortened / revised / expanded. The summary is an important aspect of the examination, as the summary will appear on the students &apos;Australian Higher Education Graduate Statement&apos; (AHEGS).


Thesis summaries need to be simple and direct, so that readers of the AHEGS can appreciate and understand the research that has been conducted and why it is important.


The summary provided is:  “INSERT SUMMARY”


Kindly forward us a revised 100 words or less summary.


Recommended format

The summary either explains the study or sets out the problem, in lay language, followed in each case by a statement of its practical application.

You can commence with either “This thesis” or see alternative example below.

Use the present tense and short, crisp sentences to describe the research and its results.

You may like to add a further sentence outlining the significance or practical value of the work.

Avoid technical or specialised terms, which cannot be readily understood by the general public.


The following is an example of an original summary which did not meet the guidelines:

This thesis examined the pathophysiology of the vascular endothelium in patients with high levels of plasma lipids. It identified a new group of patients with vascular dysfunction and established that an exercise program may be of benefit to such patients.

It was revised thus:

This thesis examines the detrimental effect of high levels of fats in the blood on blood vessel function. It identifies a new group of patients with blood vessel disorders and establishes that a home-based exercise program may be of benefit to such patients.

An example of an acceptable alternative to the format:

Tropical cyclones are an important part of the climate system, but they are not well represented in computer models of climate in general. This thesis develops a realistic and efficient modelling scheme for tropical cyclones tested under a range of conditions.

Please forward the amended thesis summary by email as soon as possible.


Kind regards

Thank you.

_______________________

​
Monash Graduate Education
Chancellery Building D
26 Sports Walk
Monash University, VIC 3800, Australia
T: +61 3 990 53009
W: www.monash.edu/graduate-research
Campus Map: www.monash.edu/campuses/clayton/
CRICOS Provider No. 00008C

We&apos;re listening….your feedback helps us improve
Follow us on Facebook: www.facebook.com/MonashGraduateEducation

{!Case.Thread_Id}</textOnly>
    <type>html</type>
</EmailTemplate>
